Guide to the Alfred E. Holcomb Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Alfred Eggleston Holcomb papers
1909-1939
MS 1007
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The Alfred Eggleston Holcomb Papers include correspondence, writings, and printed matter related to tax reform. Principal correspondents are Charles J. Bullock and Edwin R. A. Seligman, who write about their work as officers of the National Tax Association. The writing and printed matter are also concerned with questions of taxation, particularly the single tax.
Holcomb, Alfred E. (Alfred Eggleston), 1867-1956
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Alfred E. Holcomb, 1952.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Alfred E. Holcomb Papers consist of correspondence, writings, and printed matter related to his activities as a tax reformer. The correspondence, 1913-34, is mainly with Charles J. Bullock and Edwin R. A. Seligman about their work as officers of the National Tax Association. The writings (mainly carbon copies of typed manuscripts by Holcomb and others) deal with the single tax, taxation of national banks, and other proposed reforms of property taxation. The printed matter consists mainly of pamphlets and broadsides published during campaigns for the single tax in the United States and Canada in the 1910s and early 1920s.
Economics; Law; Single tax; Taxation; Lawyers; Bullock, Charles Jesse, 1869-1941; Holcomb, Alfred E. (Alfred Eggleston), 1867-1956; Seligman, Edwin R. A. (Edwin Robert Anderson), 1861-1939; National Tax Association
- Inventory
  - National Tax Association: correspondence and other papers, 1913-1934, 1939, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 10)
  - Federal law on state taxation of national banks: writings, transcriptions, and printed bills, 1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Opinions regarding construction of Ch. 897 of the Laws of the State of New York, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - H. L. Lutz: "The Problem of National Bank Taxation, with Special Reference to California", 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Notes on the Bank Tax Situation", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Taxation of national banks: printed matter, 1917-1935 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Banks: financial data, [1929?] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Single tax
    - Letters, articles, copies of printed matter, 1911-1919 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - California [leaflets], 1916, 1920, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - New York [leaflets], undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Oregon [pamphlets, leaflets], 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Toronto [pamphlet], 1923 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Vancouver [pamphlet], [1914] (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - United States [pamphlets, leaflets, articles], 1909-1919 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Weir v. Jaybird: correspondence, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Draft inheritance tax law, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Classified property tax: writings, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Separation of tax sources: writings, correspondence, transcriptions, 1912-1916 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Montana, Attorney General: opinion regarding the constitutionality of different rates of assessment and taxation for different kinds of property, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Samuel T. Howe: "The Central Control of the Valuation of Taxable Subjects", undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Connecticut (State), Municipal Tax Division: "Taxation of National Banks with Special Reference to Connecticut", 1930 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Albert Jay Nock: articles in The American Magazin e, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1913-1918 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1915-1934 (Box 3, Folder 33)